In a land on the brink of war the most dangerous place to be is in love.
The Ottoman Lieutenant is a romance, drama, war film directed by Joseph Ruben.
Lillie, a determined American woman, ventures overseas to join Dr.
Jude at a remote medical mission in the Ottoman Empire (now Turkey).
However, Lillie soon finds herself at odds with Jude and the mission’s founder, Woodruff, when
she falls for the titular military man, Ismail, just as the war is about to erupt.
Lillie Rowe, played by Hera Hilmar.
Ismail Veli, played by Michiel Huisman.
Jude Gresham, played by Josh Hartnett.
Woodruff, played by Ben Kingsley.
Khalil Bey, played by Haluk Bilginer.
Melih Pasha, played by Selçuk Yöntem.
The Ottoman Lieutenant (Turkish: Osmanlı Subayı) is a Turkish-American romantic war
drama film directed by Joseph Ruben and written by Jeff Stockwell.
The film stars Michiel Huisman, Hera Hilmar, Josh Hartnett and Ben Kingsley.
The film was released widely on March 10, 2017.
The film was released around the period of the film The
Promise, a film depicting the Armenian genocide.
The perceived similarities between the films resulted in accusations that
The Ottoman Lieutenant existed to deny the Armenian genocide.
The film explores themes of nurse, world war i,
lieutenant, 1910s, ottoman empire.
The tone is emotional.